<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://liang-alan.github.io</id>
    <title>3407</title>
    <updated>2020-05-14T15:53:42.898Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liang-alan.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://liang-alan.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>3407</subtitle>
    <logo>https://liang-alan.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://liang-alan.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, 3407</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[团队成员]]></title>
        <id>https://liang-alan.github.io/post/tuan-dui-cheng-yuan/</id>
        <link href="https://liang-alan.github.io/post/tuan-dui-cheng-yuan/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-05-14T12:49:27.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589469487247.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<h1 id="孔令杰-副教授-博导">孔令杰 副教授、博导</h1>
<p>2016年入选第十三批“千人计划”青年项目。2012年在清华大学获得工学博士学位，随后在哈佛大学、霍华德·休斯医学研究所Janelia研究校园、普渡大学从事博士后研究，2017年加入清华大学精密仪器系。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589469509324.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="郭晶晶-博士后">郭晶晶 博士后</h1>
<p>2018年1月获得清华大学博士学位。2018.4加入。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589469672536.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="靳程">靳程</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2018.9至今）。本科：北京理工大学。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589469867836.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="施汝恒">施汝恒</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2018.9至今）。本科：四川大学。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589470300163.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="周冰倩">周冰倩</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2019.9至今）。本科：清华大学。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589470393271.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="刘驰">刘驰</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2019.9至今）。本科：中国科学技术大学。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589470566697.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="翟家振">翟家振</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2020.9至今）。本科：南开大学。<br>
<img src="https://liang-alan.github.io/post-images/1589470842168.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<h1 id="梁君浩">梁君浩</h1>
<p>博士研究生（2020.9至今）。本科：西安电子科技大学。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[发表论文]]></title>
        <id>https://liang-alan.github.io/post/fa-biao-lun-wen/</id>
        <link href="https://liang-alan.github.io/post/fa-biao-lun-wen/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-05-14T12:41:17.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="2019">2019</h1>
<ol>
<li>Ruheng Shi, Cheng Jin, Hao Xie, Yuanlong Zhang, Xinyang Li, Qionghai Dai, and Lingjie Kong, Multi-plane, wide-field fluorescent microscopy for biodynamic imaging in vivo, Biomedical Optics Express 10(12), 6625-6635 (2019)</li>
<li>Xinyang Li, Yuanlong Zhang, Kan Liu, Hao Xie, Haoqian Wang, Lingjie Kong, and Qionghai Dai, Adaptive optimization for axial multi-foci generation in multiphoton microscopy, Optics Express 27(24), 35948-35961 (2019)</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Bingqian Zhou, Changxi Yang, Qionghai Dai, and Lingjie Kong， Stretchable and upconversion-luminescent polymeric optical sensor for wearable multifunctional sensing， Optics Letters 44(23), 5747-5750 (2019)</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo*, Changxi Yang, Qionghai Dai，and Lingjie Kong*，Soft and Stretchable Polymeric Optical Waveguide-Based Sensors for Wearable and Biomedical Applications，Sensors 2019, 19(17), 3771; https://doi.org/10.3390/s19173771</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo，Bingqian Zhou，Rui Zong，Longsheng Pan，Xuemei Li，Xinguang Yu，Changxi Yang，Lingjie Kong*，Qionghai Dai，A Stretchable and Highly Sensitive Optical Strain Sensor for Human-Activity Monitoring and Healthcare， ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces (2019)， https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.9b09815</li>
<li>Jingtao Fan*, Jinli Suo*, Jiamin Wu*, Hao Xie*, Yibing Shen, Feng Chen, Guijin Wang, Liangcai Cao, Guofan Jin, Quansheng He, Tianfu Li, Guoming Luan, Lingjie Kong#, Zhenrong Zheng# &amp; Qionghai Dai#, Video-rate imaging of biological dynamics at centimetre scale and micrometre resolution, Nature Photonics (2019), https://doi.org/10.1038/s41566-019-0474-7 (*共同第一作者，#共同通讯作者)</li>
<li>Yuanlong Zhang#, Tiankuang Zhou#, Xuemei Hu, Xinyang Li, Hao Xie, Lu Fang, Lingjie Kong,* and Qionghai Dai, Overcoming tissue scattering in wide-field two-photon imaging by extended detection and computational reconstruction, Optics Express, 27(15), 20117-20132 (2019)</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Bingqian Zhou, Changxi Yang, Qionghai Dai, and Lingjie Kong, Stretchable and Temperature‐Sensitive Polymer Optical Fibers for Wearable Health Monitoring, Advanced Functional Materials, https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.201902898</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Kangjun Zhao, Bingqian Zhou, Wen Ning, Kaili Jiang, Changxi Yang, Lingjie Kong, and Qionghai Dai, Wearable and Skin‐Mountable Fiber‐Optic Strain Sensors Interrogated by a Free‐Running, Dual‐Comb Fiber Laser, Advanced Optical Materials, https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.201900086</li>
<li>Yuanlong Zhang, Xinyang Li, Hao Xie, Lingjie Kong*, and Qionghai Dai, Hybrid spatio-spectral coherent adaptive compensation for line-scanning temporal focusing microscopy, J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 52, 024001 (2019) （入选Emerging Leaders 2019专辑）</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2018">2018</h1>
<ol>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Hanxi Huang, Minjuan Zhou, Changxi Yang, and Lingjie Kong*, Quantum Dots-Doped Tapered Hydrogel Waveguide for Ratiometric Sensing of Metal Ions, Anal. Chem. 90 (20), 12292-12298 (2018)</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Yuqing Luo, Changxi Yang, and Lingjie Kong*, In situ surface-enhanced Raman scattering sensing with soft and flexible polymer optical fiber probes, Optics Letters 43 (21), 5443-5446 (2018)</li>
<li>Yuanlong Zhang, Lingjie Kong, Hao Xie, Xiaofei Han, and Qionghai Dai, Enhancing axial resolution and background rejection in line-scanning temporal focusing microscopy by focal modulation，Optics Express, Vol. 26, Issue 17, pp. 21518-21526 (2018)</li>
<li>Jingjing Guo, Yihang Ding, Xiaosheng Xiao, Lingjie Kong*, and Changxi Yang*, Multiplexed static FBG strain sensors by dual-comb spectroscopy with a free running fiber laser, Opt. Express 26(13), 16147-16154 (2018) (* co-corresponding author)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong, Yifeng Zhou, and Meng Cui, Large-field-of-view imaging by multi-pupil adaptive optics, SPIE Photonics West 2018, Paper 10502-9 (Invited Paper)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2017">2017</h1>
<ol>
<li>Ziwei Li, Jia Hou, Jinli Suo, Chang Qiao, Lingjie Kong, and Qionghai Dai, “Contrast and resolution enhanced optical sectioning in scattering tissue using line-scanningtwo-photon structured illumination microscopy”, Optics Express 25(25), 32010-32020 (2017)</li>
<li>Yan Li, Xiaosheng Xiao, Lingjie Kong, and Changxi Yang, “Fiber Supercontinuum Source for Broadband-CARS Microspectroscopy Based on a Dissipative Soliton Laser”, IEEE Photonics Journal 9(4), 3900807 (2017)</li>
<li>Jung-Hoon Park*, Lingjie Kong*, Yifeng Zhou and Meng Cui，Large-field-of-view imaging by multi-pupil adaptive optics, Nature Methods 2017, doi:10.1038/nmeth.4290 (*共一作)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2016">2016</h1>
<ol>
<li>Kong, L. and Cui, M., In vivo imaging flow cytometry based on laser-scanning two-photon microscopy at kHz cross-sectional frame rate, SPIE Photonics West 2016, San Francisco, CA, Feb. 13-18 (2016), paper 9712-59 (JenLab Young Investigator Award Paper)</li>
<li>Kong, L. and Cui, M., Volumetric imaging of fast biological dynamics in deep tissue via wavefront engineering, SPIE Photonics West 2016, San Francisco, CA, Feb. 13-18 (2016), paper 9717-18 (特邀报告)</li>
<li>Kong, L., In vivo volumetric imaging of fast biological dynamics in deep tissue via wavefront engineering, International Conference on Laser Application in Life Science, Shenzhen, China, Oct. 14-18 (2016) (特邀报告)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong#, Justin P. Little, and Meng Cui#, &quot;Motion quantification during functional imaging in awake behaving animals,&quot; Biomedical Optics Express, 7(9), 3686 (2016)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong, Jianyong Tang, and Meng Cui, “In vivo volumetric imaging of biological dynamics in deep tissue via wavefront engineering, ” Optics Express 24 (2), 1214-1221 (2016)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong#, Jianyong Tang, and Meng Cui#, &quot;Multicolor, multiphoton in vivo imaging flow cytometry,&quot; Optics Express 24 (6), 6126-6135 (2016) (#共通讯作者)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong# and Meng Cui#, “In vivo Deep Tissue Imaging via Iterative Multi-photon Adaptive Compensation Technique,” IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Quantum Electronics, 22 (4), 6803010 (2016) (特邀论文, #共通讯作者)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2015">2015</h1>
<ol>
<li>Kong, L. and Cui, M., High-speed in vivo volumetric deep tissue imaging by remote focusing and wavefront compensation, Proc. of SPIE 9335-14 (2015) (特邀报告)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong and Meng Cui, &quot;In vivo neuroimaging through the highly scattering tissue via iterative multi-photon adaptive compensation technique,&quot; Optics Express 23, 6145-6150 (2015)</li>
<li>Lingjie Kong, Jianyong Tang, Justin P. Little, Yang Yu, Tim Lämmermann, Charles P. Lin, Ronald N. Germain and Meng Cui, &quot;Continuous volumetric imaging via an optical phase-locked ultrasound lens, &quot; Nature Methods 12, 759–762 (2015)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2014">2014</h1>
<ol>
<li>Lingjie Kong and Meng Cui, &quot;In vivo fluorescence microscopy via iterative multi-photon adaptive compensation technique,&quot; Optics Express 22, 23786-23794 (2014)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2013">2013</h1>
<ol>
<li>Lingjie Kong*, Minbiao Ji*, Gary R. Holtom, Dan Fu, Christian W. Freudiger, and X. Sunney Xie，&quot;Multi-color stimulated Raman scattering microscopy with a rapidly tunable optical parametric oscillator,&quot; Optics Letters 38(2), 145-147 (2013)</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="2012">2012</h1>
<ol>
<li>L. J. Kong*, L. M. Zhao*, S. Lefrancois, …, and F. W. Wise,&quot;Generation of megawatt peak power picosecond pulses from a divided-pulse fiber amplifier, &quot; Optics Letters 37(2), 253-255 (2012) (*共第一作者)</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>